Thomas Henry Huxley Papers 1851-1895 Mss.B.H981
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 1851-1895; 2 boxes; 0.5 linear feet
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1871 May 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Christie, William Dougal, 1816-1874, 1871 May 27; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 3p. Wishers him success, but does not want to be associated with the group, since he cannot spend time with it.
  - ALS to Cole, Henry, Sir, 1808-1882, 1871 June 19; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 8.) Regrets to refuse an invitation.
  - ALS to Cole, Henry, Sir, 1808-1882, 1871 June 20; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 9.) Will now be able to accept the invitation.
  - ALS to Williamson, William Crawford, 1816-1895, 1871 June27; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Cole, Henry, Sir, 1808-1882, July 22, 1871; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
    Scope and Contents
    London, A.L.S. 3p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 10.) Asks a favor.
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1871 July 25; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1871 August 17; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Williamson, William Crawford, 1816-1895, 1871 October 2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Evans, John, Sir, 1823-1908?, 1872 April 14; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 11.) Friendly letter.
  - ALS to Bartley, George C. T. (George Christopher Trout), Sir, 1842-1910, 1872 May 23; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    Envelope
  - ALS to Cole, Henry, Sir, 1808-1882, 1872 June 11; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 12.) Friendly letter.
  - ALS to Tyndall, John, 1820-1893, 1872 June 20; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Hutton, Richard Holt, 1826-1897, 1872 July 9; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1872 September 18; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1872 November 2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Mr. MacGregor, 1873 March 16; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 2p. Will be glad to see Ramsay. Goes to town.
  - ALS to Wallace, Alfred Russel, 1823-1913, 1873 April 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1873 April 25; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Clark, 1873 May 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    South Kensington, A.L.S. 4p. Regimen for the day for his health. "Six children & the wife all down with" chicken pox.
  - ALS to Lymons, G. J., 1873 May 16; Royal Society of London (Box 1)
    Signed by Huxley
  - ALS to Donnelly, John, Sir, 1873 May 31; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 13.) Friendly letter.
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1873 June 18; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to "My dear Principal", 1873 September 26; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 4p. Is too rushed trying to train teachers to visit on this important occasion.
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1873 October 18; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1873 November 18; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - Ca. 1873?, Lockyer, J. Norman (Box 1)
    Broadside; signed by C. Darwin
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1874 March 16; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Seeley, Harry Govier, 1839-1909, 1874 April 1; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Seeley, Harry Govier, 1839-1909, 1874 April 14; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1874 April 16; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Appleton, Charles, 1874 July 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 4p. Cannot say about the American business. Is not disappointed about lack of recognition from the English universities.
  - ALS to Carpenter, William, 1874 July 18; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Miss Frick, 1874 July 30; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    London, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning her Godfather.
  - ALS to Appleton, Charles, 1874 October 21; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 2p. Agrees with his ideas on education.
  - ALS to Appleton, Charles, 1875 January 28; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 3p. Likes his plan and would like to improve it. Concerning his lecture tour. Darwin.
  - ALS to Davy, W. G., 1875 February 26; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    With envelope
  - ALS to Appleton, Charles, 1875 March 3; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 4p. Cannot help him in the Athenaeum. Does not see how they can keep the railroads out of the Lake District, nor see how they can make a park of the area without purchasing all of it.
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1875 April 24; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1875 April 29; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1875 May 11; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1875 June 5; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1875 June 14; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Williamson, William Crawford, 1816-1895, 1875 August 26; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1875 September 14; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Appleton, Charles, 1875 November 1; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning English and American university gifts from wealthy persons and governments.
  - ALS to Hooker, 1875(?) November 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 2p. Wants draft which he, Sclater and Hooker were to prepare for Royal Institution. After reading Markham, is for an Arctic expedition.
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1875 December 4; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1875 December 21; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1875 December 31; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1875 December 31; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Miall, Louis Compton, 1842-1921, 1876 January 18; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    London, A.L.S. 3p. Asks for copy of his reprint as he is working on Amphibia.
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1876 March 5; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1876 April 15; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1876 May 5; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Martin, E. W., 1876 November 11; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Appleton, Charles, 1876 December 9; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 4p. Is not sure of anything from America, although friends are certain, for him. Concerning a child raised by the wolves.
  - ALS to Carpenter, P. H., 1877 January 10; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    With envelope. South Kensington, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning crinoidea. Refers to Semper.
  - ALS to Cole, Henry, Sir, 1808-1882, 1877 February (?) 5; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 3p. and add. (see Letters to various persons, no. 14.) Introduces Frederick Waller.
  - ALS to Godwin, Clement, 1877 April 29; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    London, A.L.S. 2p. Refuses proposal to be orator to the Medical Society.
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1877 May 2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1877 May 23; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Fowke, J. K., 1877 August 21; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 2p. Wishes a copy of the review when it is published.
  - ALS to Seeley, Harry Govier, 1839-1909, 1877 October 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Seeley, Harry Govier, 1839-1909, 1877 October 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1878 June 12; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Pollock, Henry, 1878 July 16?; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Addressed envelope to Henry Pollock. A.D.S.with initials. 1p. Removed from B: ALI.1, July 1975.
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1878 August 6; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1878 September 3; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Williamson, William Crawford, 1816-1895, 1878 October 21; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1878 November 13; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Milne-Edwards, Alphonse, 1835-1900, 1878 November 27; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    London, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning crawfishes, etc. Thanks for his assistance.
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1878 December 11; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1878 December [?]; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1879 January 2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Williamson, William Crawford, 1816-1895, 1879 March 19; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Milne-Edwards, 1879 June 4; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 4p. Acknowledges the honor afforded him by the Academy. Recalls Mr. Milne- Edwards' support on a certain occasion a quarter century before. His [Huxley's] comments on Darwin.
  - ALS to Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1820-1913, 1879 December 4; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Williamson, William Crawford, 1816-1895, 1880 June 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Usher, J., 1881 June 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning D. Brewster and the proposed border counties association.
  - ALS to Heusman, H. G., 1881 July 5; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1883 July 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Lankester, 1883 December 20; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Scott, E. L., 1884 March 11; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning his scroll.
  - ALS to Mrs. Earle, 1884 August 14; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Seeley, Harry Govier, 1839-1909, 1884 November 7; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1884 November 18; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.89 in part
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1884 December 22; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.92 in part
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1885 February 23; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.103 in full
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1885 March 30; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.109 in full
  - ALS to Huxley, Leonard, 1860-1933, 1885 December 2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    With envelope. A.L.S. 3p. and add. envelope. Is happy Leonard is at Oxford. Hopes to finish up some work "before I die."
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1885[?] December 3; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1886 March 19; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1886 July 1; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Mrs. [Elizabeth Burden-] Sanderson, 1886 July 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    London, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning Burdon Sanderson.
  - ALS to Mr. Wolfenden, 1886(?) October 4; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 3p. Wishes a business affair settled as soon as possible.
  - ALS to Forster, Balthzar, 1886 October 7; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 3p. and end. Is sorry, but must refuse the invitation, since he is unwell.
  - ALS to Cole, Henry, Sir, 1808-1882, 1887 January 21; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 15.) Friendly letter. Business.
  - ALS to Cole, Henry, Sir, 1808-1882, 1887 February 15; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 16.) Will see him tomorrow.
  - ALS to Carruthers, 1887 March 16; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 3p. Will bring paper.
  - ALS to Milne-Edwards, Alphonse, 1835-1900, 1887 March 26; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. Has located a specimen of Platyderum in the British Museum.
  - ASL to [Trustees of Manchester New College]?, 1887 June 11; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L. in 3d P. 1p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 17.) Cannot accept the invitation.
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1887 November 17; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1888 March 1; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Quilter, Harry, 1851-1907, 1888 April 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1888 April 30; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1888 October 7; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.219 in full
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1888 November 13; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1888 November 17; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1889 May 7; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1889 September 29; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1889 November 11; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1889[?] November 19; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Metcalf, L. S., 1890 February 24; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Eastbourne, A.L.S. 4p. Thanks for the honor of the request, but must preserve his strength for work which is of more interest to him.
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1890 May 6; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.271 in full
  - ALS to Endleston, E. D., Rev., 1890 September 19; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Sharp, W. T., 1891 May 2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Hodeslea, Eastbourne, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Obligations as steward at the anniversary dinner of the Newspaper Press Fund.
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1891 May 4; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1891 May 6; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1891 August 14; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.310 in full
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1891 August 26; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.311 in part
  - ALS to Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895, 1892 January 6; Hutchinson, Henry Neville? (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, John, 1892 January 17; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.352
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892March 3; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 March 4; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 March 12; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 March 18; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Thompson, Henry, Sir, 1892 April 27; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 4p. and add.envelope. Comments on his "Man's Place in Nature" publication of 30 years ago.
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 May 5; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 May 9; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.467 in full
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 May 17; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.465 in full
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 May 24; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 May 28; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Hyde Clarke, 1892 July 7; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 August 22; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.345 in part
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 October 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, John, 1892 November 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 November 15; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1892 December 25; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1892 December 25; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1893 January 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.370 in full
  - ALS to Trimen, Henry?, 1893 January 17; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning a newspaper controversy with Schäfer.
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1893 April 12; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Pub. V.II, p.67 in full
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1893 May 4; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - Calling card, 1908; Huxley, Henrietta Anne Heathorn, Mrs.
  - ALS to Collier, John, 1893 May 9; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Quilter, Harry, 1851-1907, 1893 June 7; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, 1893 August 25; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1893 December 24; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1894 March 25; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1894 May 6; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Quilter, Harry, 1851-1907, 1894 May 21?; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1894 June 24; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to "Dear Sir", 1894 June 30; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1894 July 15; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1894 October 12; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1895 February 5; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, 1895 March 6; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - 1908 May 7, Huxley, Henrietta Anne Heathorn, Mrs. (Box 2)
    Calling card
  - ALS to Carpenter, William B., 1813-1885, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    April 20
  - ALS to C[ole?], A., n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 19.) Will see him shortly.
  - ALS to Cole, Henry, Sir, 1808-1882, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. with initials. 1p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 20.) Can do no public speaking.
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    "Dearest Babs"
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    "Dearest Ethel"
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Collier, Ethel Huxley, 1866-1941, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    "Baby Addle"
  - ALS to Donnelly, John, Sir, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters to various persons, no. 21.) Friendly letter.
  - ALS to Flower, William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    July 10
  - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Pollock, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    Museum of Practical Geology, A.L.S. 1p. Accepts dinner invitation for Saturday the 27th.
  - ALS to Pye-Smith, Philip Henry, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to Quekett, John Thomas, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letter.
  - ALS to Seeley, Harry Govier, 1839-1909, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    April 22
  - ALS to Williamson, William Crawford(?), 1816-1895, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - ALS to "My dear Sir", n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
    - ALS to Knowles, James, Sir, 1831-1908, 1873 October 8; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 1)
  - ALS to ?, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895 (Box 2)
  - Calling card, n.d.; Huxley, Henrietta Anne Heathorn, Mrs. (Box 2)
    Sketch of jellyfish - to Ethel Collier?
  - We venture to state..., undated; Lockyer, J. Norman
    the following reasons for the subsidy on a large scale of research unencumbered with teaching... Printed D.S. Joseph N. Lockyer and C. E. Appleton. With signature of Ch. Darwin. 2p., end. n.p., n.d. [ca.1875].
  - Letters to various persons, n.d.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895